<?xml version='1.0'?> 
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY appversion "3.90"> 
  <!ENTITY date "May 2003"> 
  <!ENTITY app "<application>xfwm4</application>">
]>

<article id="xfwm4" lang="en">

<!-- Header --> 
<articleinfo>

  <title>XFce 4 Window Manager</title>
  
  <copyright>
    <year>2003</year> <holder>AUTHOR</holder>
  </copyright>

<!-- translators: uncomment this:

  <copyright>
   <year>2002</year> <holder>ME-THE-TRANSLATOR (Latin
   translation)</holder>
  </copyright>

 -->

<!-- I don't know about this
  <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
    <para>
      This document is provided under the terms of the GNU GPL, version
      2 or (at your option) any later version.
    </para>
  </legalnotice>
-->
  <authorgroup>

    <author>
      <firstname>MAIN</firstname> <surname>AUTHOR</surname>
      <affiliation>
	<address><email>m.author@users.sourceforge.net</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

<!-- This is appropriate place for other contributors: translators,
maintainers, etc. Commented out by default.

    <othercredit role="translator">
      <firstname>Latin</firstname> <surname>Translator 1</surname>
      <affiliation>
	<orgname>Latin Translation Team</orgname>
	<address><email>translator@gnome.org</email> </address>
      </affiliation> <contrib>Latin translation</contrib>
    </othercredit>
-->

  </authorgroup>

  <revhistory>
    <revision>
      <revnumber>0.1</revnumber> 
      <date>May 2003</date>
      <authorinitials>ma</authorinitials>
    </revision>
  </revhistory>

  <releaseinfo>This manual describes &app; version &appversion;
  </releaseinfo>

</articleinfo>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="wm-intro">
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>The XFce 4 Window Manager is part of the 
    <ulink url="http://www.xfce.org" 
      type="html">XFce Desktop Environment</ulink>. The actual command to 
    run is &app;. To run it in the background use 
    <command>&app; --daemon</command>. The window manager is responsible for
    the placement of windows on the screen, provides the window
    decorations and allows you for instance to move, resize or close them.
  </para>

  <para>If you are familiar with previous versions of XFce you will find many
    changes. First of all, &app; adheres strongly to the standards defined on
    <ulink linkend="http://freedesktop.org"
      type="html">freedesktop.org</ulink>. Consequently, special features such
    as making windows borderless, or providing an icon for the application
    must now be implemented in the application; you can no longer use the
    window manager to force different behaviour. Most visible change is
    probably the themeability. The window decorations (borders, title bar and
    window buttons) can be configured by using window manager themes. 
  </para>

</sect1>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="wm-using">
  <title>Using &app;</title>

  <sect2 id="wm-windows">
    <title>Windows</title>
  
    <para>The window manager provides borders, a title bar and window buttons to
      application windows. The look is defined by the window manager theme. The
      edges and corners of the window frame can be used to resize a window,
      although certain special windows can not be resized.
    </para>
    
    <para>
      In the default theme &app; shows six buttons and a title on regular 
      application windows. The six buttons perform these basic functions: 
      menu, shade, stick, minimize, mizimize and close.
    </para>

  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="wm-keybindings">
    <title>Keyboard shortcuts</title>

    <para>&app; also provides a limited number of keyboard shortcuts to
      quickly perform certain tasks. Although the default configuration should
      work fine for everyone it is possible to redefine the key combinations
      by making a personal keybinding configuration file.
    </para>

    <para>In the default configuration the following kybindings are defined:
    </para>

  </sect2>

</sect1>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="wm-settings">
  <title>Customizing &app;</title>


</sect1>

  <!-- extra space -->
  <para>&nbsp;</para>
  
<sect1 id="wm-copyright">
  <title>About &app;</title>

  <para>&app; was written Olivier Fourdan  
    (<email>fourdan@xfce.org</email>). To find more information, please visit 
    the <ulink url="http://www.xfce.org" type="http">XFce web site</ulink>. 
  </para>

  <para>To report a bug or make a suggestion regarding this application or
    this manual send an e-mail to the xfce4-dev mailing list, or use the bug 
    tracking system at the 
    <ulink url="http://sourceforge.net/projects/xfce" type="http">XFce 
      sourceforge project site</ulink>. 
  </para>
    
  <para> This program is distributed under the terms of the
    GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; 
    either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.
  </para>

  <para>You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License 
    along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software 
    Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place - Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307, 
    USA.
  </para>

</sect1>

</article>
